Alexander James Lea

Address: The Superintendent's House, Worsham, Witney, Oxfordshire, OX29 ORX

Email Address: alexander.lea@students.plymouth.ac.uk

Mobile Telephone: 07943 534 575

Personal Profile

Final year student, studying Bsc(Hons) Computing at Plymouth University. I have practical industrial experience working within an IT department; last academic year, I undertook an industrial placement year at BMW Group UK. Academically, I achieved more than 70% in both my first and second years of university, resulting in my inclusion in the 2012 and 2013 Dean's List of Academic Achievement.

Relevant Work Experience

During my industrial placement, I worked as a C# ASP.NET developer within a small team. I was able to provide significant contributions to group projects, as well as successfully manage my own projects and present research and project proposals to my colleagues. Whilst at BMW, I worked on different areas of an IT project, gaining practical experience in the software development life cycle. Making use of excellent communication skills, I developed and maintained successful working relationships with both external and internal staff.

Skills

Software Development

- Strong ability coding in C# and ASP.NET, and worked as a C# ASP.NET developer during my placement year. While on placement, I worked as the sole developer for a C# application that managed training administration for BMW Group UK.
- Competent in Java, HTML, CSS, PHP, and a partial knowledge of C/C++.
- A knowledge of theoretical programming concepts, allowing me to quickly and effectively learn other languages.
- Able to think logically and laterally, and as a result I am able to solve problems efficiently.

System Requirements Analysis

- Competent in the complete software development process, I worked in many areas within a development team during my placement, which allowed me to develop an understanding of how the different aspects of a project come together. I have first-hand experience of the perils related to working on projects with badly defined requirements.
- A working knowledge of UML data modelling, and the ability to model systems using use-case and activity diagrams.

Communication

- Strong presentation skills, demonstrated during placement year when I was required to present proposals and solutions to internal staff of differing hierarchical levels.
- Able to confidently and concisely convey my opinions and point of view. At university, I am an active member of the debating society, regularly debating in front of an audience.
- While volunteering at the London 2012 Olympics, it was necessary for me to communicate with a very wide variety of people, some with disabilities and diverse ethnic backgrounds. This demonstrated to me the importance of conciseness, as well as clearly enunciated speech.
- Able to formulate structured arguments and eloquently convey findings or opinions in a formal written document.
- Practical experience writing project documentation both at university and during my placement, where the importance of complete and up to date documentation was demonstrated to me.

Database Analysis

- Confident in designing, creating, querying and managing SQL-based database systems, and have some experience with PL/SQL.

- Practical experience of Oracle and PostgreSQL database systems gained at university, during my placement year, and completing personal projects.

Teamwork

- Work effectively as a member of a team, and I relish the challenge of responsibility. I have been the group leader for a number of University projects, and took the role of Project Owner during a SCRUM development-scenario.
- While I enjoy leading, I am also able to work respectfully and diligently within a team; during my placement, I was required to work closely with a large and diverse network of co-workers, and could not have successfully completed my day-to-day role without working successfully within a team.

Time Management and Organisation

Confident in managing my workload, and organising my work and projects. Whilst working at BMW, I was
given the responsibility to manage my own time and projects, and was able to successfully deliver my
projects to the clients on time.

Education and Qualifications

2011 - present Plymouth University

Bsc(Hons) Computing Predicted 1st Class Final year modules:

Object-Orientated Web Application Development
Advanced Databases and Their Applications
API Software Development
Software Development and Project Management
Advanced Web Technologies

2004 - 2011 **Burford School**

3 A-levels, 2 AS-levels, 11 GCSEs

Employment

August 2013 – August 2014 BMW Group UK (Oxford), Industrial Placement - XS Apps Developer

July 2012 - September 2012 Maison Blanc (Burford), Kitchen Assistant

October 2009 - September 2011 Burford Garden Company (Burford), Sales Assistant

Voluntary/Unpaid Experience

26th July 2012 - 12th August 2012 London 2012 Olympics, Transport Team Member 7th July 2008 - 18th July 2008 Jackson-Stops & Staff (Burford), General Assistant

Interests

I take an interest in current affairs because, living in the world we do, I believe it is impossible to have an informed opinion without first taking into account those of others. I relish the opportunity to debate my point of view, and debate competitively with university, as well as holding a committee role, as competition coordinator. I also rock climb, cycle and love cooking, especially baking cakes and pastries; I find cooking a great stress relief, and I enjoy the challenge of attempting new recipes — or altering old ones — to achieve the 'perfect' result.

Referees

Professional: Richard Rigden, MINI Plant Oxford, Eastern Bypass Road, Oxford, OX4 6NL; richard.rigden@bmwgroup.com; 01865 824 000

Academic: Nathan Clarke, Plymouth University, Drake Circus, Plymouth, Devon, PL4 8AA; n.clarke@plymouth.ac.uk; 01752 586 218